Register of the Paul Crouch Papers, 1925-1958
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul Crouch Papers,
1925-1958
70045
Crouch, Paul, 1903-1955
17 manuscript boxes (7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, transcripts of court testimony, correspondence, and clippings, relating to communism in the United States, especially in Hawaii, and to the anti-communist movement. Includes typescript memoirs, entitled "Broken Chains."
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Communist Party of the United States of America; Anti-communist movements--United States; Communism; Communism--Hawaii; Communism--United States; Hawaii; United States--Politics and government
Container List
- Subpoena to Paul Crouch to appear March 6, 1953, at Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. (Box 1.)
- Typewritten manuscript entitled "Brief History of the Communist Movement in North and South Carolina" by Paul Crouch
- Typewritten manuscript entitled "Communism in Latin America" by Paul Crouch
- Typewritten manuscript entitled "The Organizational Structure of the Communist Movement" by Paul and Sylvia Crouch
- Testimony before the Florida Legislative Investigating Commission and the U.S. Senate Subcommittee, Washington, D.C.
- Correspondence
- Testimony and biographical information concerning Sylvia Crouch
- Miscellaneous handwritten, typewritten, and mimeographed materials
- Miscellaneous handwritten, typewritten, and mimeographed materials (Box 2.)
- Documents refuting charges against Paul Crouch
- Text of various Crouch testimony
- Photocopy of resolutions made at the 6th World Congress of the Communist International- 1928
- Originals and photocopies of "The New South," 1938-1939
- Photocopies of the "Young Worker," 1925-1928
- File cards and lists of persons known to Paul Crouch as CPUSA members (Box 3-4.)
- Newspapers clippings relating to Paul Crouch (Box 5.)
  - 1945-1950
  - 1951-1953 (Box 6.)
  - 1954 (Box 7.)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 8.)
- Newspaper clippings pertaining to Paul Crouch testimony before the U.S. Senate Internal Security Sub-Committee (Box 9-15.)
- Clippings dealing with the trial of Harry Bridges (Box 15.)
- Communism in Hawaii during the 1950's
- Communism in Hawaii during the 1950's (Box 16.)
- Miscellaneous documents, reports, manuscripts, clippings, etc., regarding the political careers of Paul and Sylvia Crouch
- Typewritten manuscript, "Broken Chains," by Paul Crouch, describing his career in the U.S. Communist Party, 1925-1942 (Box 17.)